<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on Benjamin Listwon</title>
    <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/tags/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinion on Benjamin Listwon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://benjaminlistwon.com/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving Deeper on Tesla and Consumer Protections</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/diving-deeper-on-tesla-and-consumer-protections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/diving-deeper-on-tesla-and-consumer-protections/</guid>
      <description>Tesla v Fortune Just a few hours after I posted yesterday, a couple different folks directed me to Tesla’s blog post regarding the Joshua Brown’s fatal crash on ‘autopilot’ and an article by Fortune that is critical of Tesla and CEO Elon Musk.
It took me some time to digest both pieces, as well as some additional information surrounding them, but the timelines they present are clearly different than those that were more broadly reported in the media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carpetbaggers and Disruption’s Human Costs</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/carpetbaggers-and-disruptions-human-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/carpetbaggers-and-disruptions-human-costs/</guid>
      <description>Update (July 06, 8:00PM): Someone pointed out Tesla&amp;rsquo;s rebuttal to a Fortune article which presents different information about the timeline of Joshua Brown&amp;rsquo;s death. The only date I have referred to below is June 30, the date of Tesla&amp;rsquo;s press release, while it appears the accident itself occurred on May 7.
I will write more tomorrow about the new information both articles present, as well as a response to some questions about my position on innovation, &amp;lsquo;autopilot&amp;rsquo; and technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only As Hard As We Make It</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/only-as-hard-as-we-make-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/only-as-hard-as-we-make-it/</guid>
      <description>Someone recently shared a link to Has Design Become Too Hard?, an article by Jeffrey Zeldman about the changing landscape of designing for the web and the tools that we use to do that job. [1]
Ignoring the salesmanship for a moment, the article makes a couple of important points, and misses something I think we overlook in our profession: not everyone wants to do it all on their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New, New Media</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/the-new-new-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/the-new-new-media/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing about virtual reality (VR) and augmented reality (AR). (Collectively I will call them V/AR for now.)
If your expectation is something like— “But when I see The Weeknd live, I can feel the bass.” or “Part of actually being in Paris is the noise, the smell, the sound.” or “But I can’t touch the things I see.” —then you should embrace those real experiences as they are, in the present, in all their glory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Really, For Everyone</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/no-really-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/no-really-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Rob Brackett tweeted a link to A web for everyone, an article by Jeremy Keith. In that article, Jeremy discusses the need to build products for the web that are accessible to all audiences, not just those with bleeding edge functionality:
 I wish we could make offline functionality a requirement. But the reality is that not everyone is using a browser that supports the necessary technology. I wish we could make beautiful typography a requirement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalism: It Takes Effort Too</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/minimalism-it-takes-effort-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/minimalism-it-takes-effort-too/</guid>
      <description>Last Wednesday, Mike Rundle tweeted about Smartisan’s T2, an Android phone that features a completely custom UI:
Wow, Smartisan OS is a custom Android implementation with truly beautiful icons and UI work. https://t.co/Zk8Bh9gd2T pic.twitter.com/FUiqXFYYbX
— Mike Rundle (@flyosity) May 18, 2016 It looks awesome—the phone, the OS, everything. Anyway, a short time later in Slack, someone shared the same tweet and asked:
 I admit that maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t get design, because I&amp;rsquo;m not a designer by trade … but is iOS 6-style design really &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo; as many designers imply, or is it just a retro factor/change is hard/other things I may not understand?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Semantic Markup</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/on-semantic-markup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/on-semantic-markup/</guid>
      <description>The Backdrop (In which the author is, once again, too hasty.)
Yesterday, I saw this tweet pass through my timeline:
@snookca x1000 this. Reading that ALA article, I had two thoughts…
1. ALA used to have good content.
2. What year is it? Did we go *back*?
— Nathan Smith (@nathansmith) May 17, 2016 Naturally, I was immediately curious about what Jonathan had written, and what the ALA article was about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Laravel? Why Now?</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/why-laravel-why-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/why-laravel-why-now/</guid>
      <description>(Update: Can&amp;rsquo;t believe I forgot Laracasts when I wrote about the Laravel ecosystem below.)
First, a confession. I’ve only been doing “serious” Laravel development for about four or five weeks now.
In fact, it has been about a decade since I did any serious PHP development at all.
I’m still getting my hands dirty digging through how Laravel works, and I’m certainly a way off from “mastery” of the framework, but the single best way to learn a new language, technology or framework is to have a project, a timeline, and to just get cracking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>