<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Update on Benjamin Listwon</title>
    <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/tags/update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Update on Benjamin Listwon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://benjaminlistwon.com/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hooray for Hugo!</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/hooray-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/hooray-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The old site was getting a little clunky, despite being only a few months in service. I had never intended for the design to last very long in the first place, and I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to get anywhere near the level of traction I got for some posts. Thank you all for reading!
This new site is running on Hugo, an amazing static site generator written in Go. If you are looking to start any sort of content-driven site, or feel like the old one is outgrowing its roots, I encourage you to give Hugo a serious look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back In Action</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/back-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/back-in-action/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a long summer so far, but it has seemingly flown by. I know it has been a while since I’ve posted anything here, but it is for a couple of great reasons.
First, I’ve been spending some more time with my son—playing basketball, biking, hunting for blackberries (and Pokemon)—and with friends, both new and lifelong. Getting to spend time with people I love and whose opinions and outlook I value has been restorative and very welcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidbits</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/tidbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/tidbits/</guid>
      <description>Wowzers, have the days simply flown by in April! It has been a little while since my last post, and this one is going to be a brief one to be sure, but I wanted to catch up to what’s been going on this month.
Reboot! First up, May 1st Reboot is right around the corner. Just three days left to crank! If you’re launching, relaunching or just breathing new life into something on the web, you should check it out and follow #May1Reboot to see what our colleagues and community are up to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Brief #004: MySQL Backups On Forge, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/in-brief-004-mysql-backups-on-forge-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/in-brief-004-mysql-backups-on-forge-part-2/</guid>
      <description>If you read my last In Brief post, you may have tried setting up a cron job to run mysqldump nightly, gone back to check the results the following day and found a zero byte file where you expected to see a dumpfile.
-rw-rw-r-- 1 forge forge 0 Mar 5 00:00 dump-nightly.sql  Don&amp;rsquo;t worry! The backup still ran, but Forge does some auto-magic output redirection that had me guessing for a little while.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>