<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Demo on Benjamin Listwon</title>
    <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/tags/demo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Demo on Benjamin Listwon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://benjaminlistwon.com/tags/demo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Order Vue: A Vue 2.0 App</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/short-order-vue-a-vue-20-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/short-order-vue-a-vue-20-app/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday I shared some of the resources I’ve been using to move from previous releases of Vue to the new Vue 2.0 API. (BTW: I’ve got a few more links to add, thanks to some great folks on Twitter.) The biggest changes in 2.0 aren’t really in the API itself, but there are a few tricky bits here and there.
As I’ve proceeded, I’ve found it is a little easier to just start some mini projects from scratch to test out some of the new functionality, as opposed to trying to reason about how to rewrite old code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respons-O-Matic Part 2</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/respons-o-matic-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/respons-o-matic-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I pushed out Respons-O-Matic, a very simplistic tool to preview RWD layouts, without much thought to how others might use it. Unsurprisingly, a few folks had some really great feedback on their own workflows, and how to make Respons-O-Matic play nicer.
Check out the updated demo if you want to see it in action, or head to the repository on Github for the code.
Here’s what’s new or different:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respons-O-Matic</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/respons-o-matic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/respons-o-matic/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I was testing out some new layouts I’ve been working on, and I built myself a little tool to preview Responsive (RWD) layouts more easily.
I thought it might be of use to some other folks as well.
It looks like this:

And you can check out a demo or go snag the repository on Github and have at it.
Further Reading As I write in the FAQ section of the repo, Respons-O-Matic is not meant to be a substitute for real, on-device testing, or anything else for that matter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>