<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diy on Benjamin Listwon</title>
    <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/tags/diy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diy on Benjamin Listwon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://benjaminlistwon.com/tags/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case For Writing It Yourself</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/a-case-for-writing-it-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/a-case-for-writing-it-yourself/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I’ve vacillated between the two extremes of “roll your own code” and “throw together a bunch of libraries.” I suspect I’m not alone in this endless pursuit of “the best” way to build software.
In the end, we all know that each project is unique, and perhaps more importantly, its requirements will change with time. A library you rely upon today may not have all the capabilities you need tomorrow, or perhaps, after real usage data pours in, you realize you only need 1/100th of some module’s functionality and that you can easily write that bit on your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When To Look Beyond jQuery</title>
      <link>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/when-to-look-beyond-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benjaminlistwon.com/blog/when-to-look-beyond-jquery/</guid>
      <description>(Update: Forgot to include ScrollMagic. Big oops!)
Before I continue, I wanted to set forth what this post is about. It is not a teardown of jQuery or a preachy case for using such-and-such a JavaScript framework.
Rather, it is an acknowledgement of two things:
 If your target is modern browsers (really anything post IE8) and you are building something of modest size, then any library or framework, jQuery or otherwise, may be overkill.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>